[Fate Chooses You]
[Episode 36]
Xin Mei,
is Lu back?
He's not here.
Didn't he go to Chongling Valley
to transform his heart?
Grandmaster didn't return to the Valley.
What?
Lu is missing.
He knocked me out.
After I woke up,
I went to Chongling Valley,
only to find he never went.
Therefore,
out of concern for him,
we came here together.
Landlady.
What month is it?
Why have the flowers outside
suddenly bloomed?
They really did.
We were in a hurry and didn't notice.
A Great Completion Stage cultivator
is dispersing their cultivation.
Cultivators practice
between heaven and earth,
absorbing the essence of the sun and moon.
They contend
with all creation for spiritual energy.
If one day I pass away,
I will disperse my cultivation
and return it to the world.
You're so powerful.
You won't die.
No one can live forever.
Everyone has to die eventually.
When that time comes,
don't cry.
Master!
♪ Spending a lifetime,
I ask myself what I first sought ♪
♪ What is it my heart truly desires? ♪
Senior.
Good.
Great.
Wonderful.
♪ Step by step up the immortal stairway ♪
♪ Paved with countless lost souls ♪
Senior,
I didn't fail your trust.
♪ Who would dare destroy the ladder
to immortality and end the path? ♪
I finally found
your child.
♪ The sun blazes over the earth ♪
♪ Yet it cannot warm
every cold home below ♪
♪ I've heard cries that rend the heavens ♪
♪ I hear the shame of parting ♪
♪ This immortal path admired by all ♪
♪ Can exist, or not exist ♪
♪ Once again I see
the world's cold indifference ♪
♪ Bending what I've cherished
all my life ♪
♪ Illusions and vanity blind the eyes,
how could one still care ♪
♪ So that all may share in ♪
Master!
♪ The road to immortality ♪
♪ I fear not defying
immortal laws and sacred precepts ♪
Master!
♪ I'm mocked
for being laughably confused ♪
♪ My solitary voice
will echo through the valley ♪
♪ They speak of immortal grace
and mystic arts ♪
♪ Is there still a trace
of compassion? ♪
♪ Realize my heart
seeks no personal gain ♪
♪ Realize my hands
remain unstained by blood ♪
♪ Realize this life still,
as always, pursues the Dao ♪
♪ Having seen the widespread devastation ♪
♪ How could I look on and ignore it? ♪
♪ I do not fear returning to dust ♪
♪ I walk this path alone ♪
♪ To let all walk ♪
♪ The road to immortality ♪
♪ I fear not defying
immortal laws and sacred precepts ♪
♪ Let sin be punished,
let desire be destroyed ♪
♪ Yet the heart must never be forsaken ♪
[Xin Xie Manor]
Aren't you going back
to your auntie's house in Wei County?
Why haven't you left yet?
But I can't bear to leave you, Master.
And Sheng.
Why can't you?
You'll be back in a few days.
If I'm not here,
who's going to cook for you?
There are restaurants in town.
I'll just take her out to eat.
Any chef
cooks better than you.
But...
Be honest with me.
Are you a bit scared?
It's natural to feel anxious
about going home.
What's there to be afraid of?
Master.
After I left home,
my father passed away.
Not long after,
my mother also passed away.
And later,
the elders of the clan
passed away one after another.
Only I remained unchanged
since I left home.
Sometimes I feel
very close to Wei County,
because it is my hometown.
But at other times,
it feels unfamiliar,
because it is completely different
from the hometown in my memory.
How about this?
You go back first.
If you feel uncomfortable,
just come back.
If someone bullies you,
come back too.
I will always stand up for you.
But you must remember,
Xin Xie Manor will always be your home.
For a person,
having a place to return to
brings peace of mind.
Thank you, Master.
Go now.
Then take good care of yourself.
I'm leaving.
Go ahead.
Master,
wait for me to come back.
I will bring you
peach blossom wine. Your favorite .
Here.
Have some soup.
Where are they?
Is everyone there?
They are also eating.
We still have some time.
Actually, I had long known
that my master's life
was coming to an end.
This time, I came out
to find the Immortality Pill
to prolong his life.
But I didn't expect
that not only did I fail
to bring back the Immortality Pill,
but I couldn't even see him
one last time.
It was my fault.
I should have returned
to Xin Xie Manor earlier.
It was all my fault.
If I hadn't
forced your marriage,
it wouldn't have ended up
like this.
This matter cannot end like this.
I will kill Li Mofu
to avenge my master.
I also want everyone in Tianyuan Sect
involved in this matter
to be held accountable.
Okay.
They definitely will.
After the battle at Sihe Library,
we fell into the hands
of Qinghong Sect.
They
could have just captured us,
but instead
they've been trying to deceive me.
It was just to get me
to help them translate
the ancient book
written in War Demon script.
Is there something wrong with this book?
Look.
This...
This is Wusheng Formation!
Back then, the War Demons
used this formation
to open the heavenly ladder.
That's right.
Wusheng Formation means
creating existence from nothing.
This formation uses human vitality
to stimulate the growth of plants.
A strand of hair just now
was enough to promote its growth.
But for a massive spiritual plant
like the Jianmu Tree,
it requires the sacrifice
of more human lives
to stimulate its growth.
Grandmaster,
the book you translated back then
also had this formation?
At that time,
he dispersed the parts of the text
related to the formation
and hid them
in other sections of the book.
It was only afterwards,
when I recalled many
inconsistent parts,
that I vaguely guessed
he wanted this formation.
I have also been wondering
who exactly is behind
Qinghong Sect.
Later, I inferred
that after we came back,
the first immortal sect to cause trouble
was likely the mastermind behind it all.
So you knocked me out
to find out
the person behind them?
It's Tianyuan Sect.
After I went up the mountain,
I found Bai Zongying imprisoned.
Through him,
I found the truth.
They also want to grow the Jianmu Tree?
Back then,
when the War Demons grew the Jianmu Tree,
if it weren't for
the Twelve Immortal Sects
and the High Priest of Youhu Clan
joining forces to suppress it,
I'm afraid this world
would have already been plunged
into misery and suffering.
How dare Tianyuan Sect
risk universal condemnation
and do such a thing?
Well, they did it anyway.
What can you do about it?
I used the Sunblock
to deal a heavy blow
to the Jianmu Tree seed.
But I still couldn't
completely destroy it.
Next,
they will definitely take action.
We...
Qianqiao,
what's wrong?
Qianqiao!
Qianqiao, what's wrong?
What's going on?
Lu Qianqiao!
Qianqiao!
Why sigh over
what you have never had?
Like an illusion,
a dream wakes to emptiness.
By the misty river, the music rises.
I only regret
that we may never meet again.
Young sir,
where are you heading?
Lanshui Town.
Lanshui Town?
Lanshui Town in Xiangzhou...
is my hometown.
Old sir, why are you laughing?
You say that is your hometown,
but you can't even get the name right.
It used to be called Lanshui Town.
But later, in a provincial exam,
3 scholars from that place
passed in a single year,
so it was renamed Sanyuan Town.
It has been many years.
You haven't been home for a long time,
have you?
Indeed, it has been quite a while.
So this time
you are going home to visit your parents?
My parents passed away early.
As for my relatives,
I haven't contacted them for a long time.
I don't know if they are still alive.
You don't know the name of your hometown,
nor whether your relatives
are still alive.
If your parents and relatives are gone,
can that place
still be considered your hometown?
Why are you going back?
Then where do you think
I should go?
The path you came from is unseen,
and the final destination is unknown.
Worldly affairs are ever unpredictable,
coldly passing by.
Who cares about rise and fall?
Walk your own path.
Go to your final destination.
[Jin Lun's spiritual sea]
Dozing off again.
I've been calling you for ages.
What sweet dream did you have?
I...
I dreamed that
I went to a very mysterious place.
Where did you go?
Where?
Where did I go?
Where do I go?
Your parents just passed away.
Where are you going again?
What are your plans next?
You can't
keep following me like this.
Don't you have things you want to do
or places you want to go?
Where is your final
destination?
Master?
You never joined the sect,
so why call me Master?
Let me ask you,
you lingered at the foot of the mountain
for a long time that day
but ultimately didn't come up.
Why was that?
My desires were too strong,
and lust had blinded my eyes.
I could not see the path ahead.
You think
what really stopped you
was lust?
Please enlighten me, Master.
All dharmas are without self.
All things return to stillness.
What is emptiness?
No words, no thoughts.
No abiding, no affairs.
Nothing to gain.
No contention, no display.
The wise do not argue.
When the mouth opens, spirit scatters;
when the tongue moves, disputes arise.
This is "no words."
When a pure mind stirs,
the five poisons
and seven emotions extinguish.
Evil thoughts and delusions
do not enter the mind.
This is "no thoughts."
Good.
Go on.
The mind does not cling to forms.
Do not dwell on the past.
Past and future—
do not go or stay.
This is "no abiding."
As for "no affairs"—
the mind is inherently pure and unstained.
It is only ordinary people
who bind themselves.
If my mind is like a calm lake,
then all things are easily resolved.
And what about "Nothing to gain?"
All living beings
and all things are but dust
before the eyes.
The mind seeks nothing,
so naturally there is nothing to gain.
But you were born with everything.
Family ties,
wealth, background,
and this
golden ring on your arm.
That woman is not your tribulation,
but a sharp blade
that cuts through the mists
of your delusion.
Master,
I don't understand.
People
come into this world naked,
walk through it,
and eventually leave naked too.
The final destination of all things
is a single word—nothing.
That is the freedom
of an infinite existence
beyond life and death,
transcending time and space.
But since you were born
with a lotus flower on your forehead,
carrying a profound treasure,
how can you
walk lightly through this world?
Jin Lun,
you have been deeply mired for decades.
You still haven't figured out
which path to take?
Think carefully.
Where does your true
destination lie?
Jin Lun.
Do you know
where you're going?
Have you made up your mind?
Where you are going,
I will not be.
I used to see you as a puzzle
that I wanted to solve.
But the deeper I went,
the harder it was to control myself.
Sheng,
I once truly cared for you.
I won't deny that.
But I've let it go.
No words, no thoughts.
No abiding, no affairs.
Nothing to gain.
You shouldn't be my tribulation,
nor the shackles that trap me.
The only thing truly trapping me
is myself.
What did you see?
Me.
A naked me,
with no attachments.
So where are you heading?
My heart has no desires.
♪ Honor and disgrace;
rumors and prejudice ♪
I am emptiness.
Wherever I am needed,
that's where I'll be.
♪ Everyone has their own take ♪
♪ Fingers coated in blood
and disasters brought about ♪
I have nothing,
yet I have everything.
♪ Were never what I wanted ♪
From now on,
♪ The great way is fading away,
besieged by mysterious traps ♪
in this vast world,
nothing can
stop my footsteps anymore.
♪ Who dares to treat life and death
as nothing? ♪
♪ In the blink of an eye, the body
collapses, and the soul is destroyed ♪
♪ The fire starts raging across the land ♪
♪ What do you think is ♪
♪ The most impressive farewell
in the world? ♪
♪ The endless slaughter and massacres ♪
♪ Do not wait until that thin snow
on the eaves ♪
♪ Turns a young man's hair white
before you regret it ♪
♪ When do you think ♪
♪ The bloody strife will come to an end? ♪
♪ Burn myself to prove it
without looking back ♪
♪ Holding the morning glow in hand,
I paint the world ♪
♪ The dawn light
illuminates the vast sky ♪
Senior Brother Bai ran away?
They couldn't have gone far.
I'll take some men down the mountain
and bring them back.
There's no need.
It is destiny.
Let us just go with the flow.
You're coughing again?
Have some water first.
Prepare brush and ink.
What for?
I'll write to the senior uncles
and elders of every immortal sect.
Write to them?
I'm going to expose this.
Master is acting willfully,
disregarding all living beings
in the world.
The only plan now
is to gather the strength
of all immortal sects
to stop him.
Esteemed senior uncles and elders,
Li Mofu, the leader of Tianyuan Sect,
intends to use dark arts
to grow the Jianmu Tree,
climb the heavenly ladder once again,
and reopen the Heavenly Gate.
He views all living beings as ants;
his arrogance is extreme.
The tragic Battle of Pinghu
is something we dare not forget
even today.
If the Jianmu Tree is revived,
the world will face devastation
and endless suffering.
I hope you will all lend a helping hand
to save the people from this crisis.
I sincerely plead with you
and await your favorable reply.
Tianyuan Sect,
Bai Zongying.
You're awake?
Dr. Zhu Yu said
that you used the Sunblock for too long
and absorbed too much
of its reversing power,
which your body couldn't handle,
causing the backlash.
Your heart meridian is damaged.
You must recover as soon as possible.
What should I do?
Prepare for the heart transformation
immediately
and become an ordinary person completely.
Isn't this a good thing?
The heart transformation was originally
in your plan.
And Zhu Yu and the others
are already preparing for it.
After this heart transformation,
you will be free from the curse.
We can live a good life.
Qianqiao,
don't worry.
What you should care about most right now
is yourself.
I don't want you to take risks,
nor do I want you to abandon
your long-held wish
for some so-called sense of righteous duty
to save the world.
I am very stubborn.
I just want the people I like
and care about
to be safe,
healthy, and live long.
So you must get better.
I will.
You've been waiting for him all day.
Leave now.
He won't come to see you.
I have something to say to him.
Tell me then.
I will pass on
your exact words to him.
What do you want to tell him?
No need.
Everything I want to say
is in this box.
Senior.
Is she still refusing to leave?
She asked me to give this to you.
This is her life-binding Gu.
She entrusted her life to you.
Whether she lives or dies
is entirely up to you.
He accepted it.
But now he has attained enlightenment
and taken the Path of Detachment,
distancing himself from worldly affairs.
He asked me to tell you...
All the past,
though still vivid in my mind,
feels like an illusion
when seen with a peaceful heart.
Love and hate leave no trace.
The past is like smoke,
dissipating entirely
in the wind.
Your bond is over.
You should go now.
Oh, right.
He said the celestial signs are unusual.
There will be a storm tonight.
He asked me to give you this umbrella.
Thank you.
Get lost!
Move!
Get out of my body!
Sheng,
you can't resist me.
Get out!
Get out of my body!
I am your father.
I gave you your life.
Today,
dedicate your flesh and blood to me,
and help my soul rest here
so I can be reborn.
[Rainwatch Terrace]
Father.
Did you receive the letter?
Bai Zongying
would risk the prestige of Tianyuan Sect
to expose Li Mofu.
This cannot be false.
Once the heavenly ladder is built,
disaster will descend upon the world.
The human realm
will surely be plunged
into misery and suffering.
I will take people
to Tianyuan Mountain now
to meet up with Junior.
Wait.
This battle will be dangerous,
and the future is uncertain.
Father.
This battle concerns the common people.
As the Young Sect Master
of Lingji Mountain,
it's my duty.
I haven't let you unsheathe
for many years.
Set off immediately
and march to Tianyuan Mountain.
Yes.
Senior Xia Xuanzi,
our Sect Leader would like to see you.
Lead the way.
I've long heard that you
are good at using Gu.
How did you end up like this?
I let my guard down for a moment
and was set up,
and my physical body was destroyed.
My primordial spirit
can only temporarily reside
in this body.
When I destroy
the soul of this body,
I will fully take control of it
and return to my peak.
This is your daughter.
You are really heartless.
If we talk about being heartless,
I can't compare to you.
As the head of all immortal sects,
behind the scenes, you actually...
Go on.
I've been hiding in
Sheng's spiritual sea,
fighting her for control of her body.
Back then in North Xiang,
I briefly
woke up for a short time
and learned about the whole story
of Qinghong Sect.
As for the immortal sect behind it,
I didn't think of anyone else.
Seeing you today,
my guess was indeed correct.
Sect Leader Li,
I came with sincerity.
Are you still
not going to tell me the truth?
The people of the Wushuang Society say
that the collapse of the heavenly ladder
and the departure of the gods
are the greatest mercy of the divine race.
But although it's mercy to mortals,
it's an outright abandonment
of us immortal sect members.
They cut off the path to Ascension,
intending to trap the immortal sect
in the mortal world forever.
Fellow Taoist Xia,
you are an expert in Gu.
You should know what happens
when a group of bugs is placed
in a sealed jar.
This is a massacre for the immortal sects.
We absolutely cannot just sit
and wait for death.
Fellow Taoist Xia,
are you willing to join me
to reopen the Heavenly Gate
and ascend to godhood?
What do you want to do?
Grow the Jianmu Tree
and reopen the Heavenly Gate.
What a lunatic.
However,
I like it.
Good.
There are truly too few
intelligent people in this world.
Most are hypocritical and foolish,
unfit for great tasks.
Fellow Taoist Xia,
you have both ambition
and ability.
You're similar to me.
This is a path of bloodshed.
I hope
someone can fight their way out with me.
Fellow Taoist Xia,
are you willing to join me?
Why not?
I'm late. I'm late.
Sect Master Lin,
please forgive me.
Hasn't Lingxu Sect
always been Tianyuan Sect's
lackey?
Why are you here today?
I do want immortality,
but I disdain using such methods
in exchange for my own life.
If I were to defy the natural order,
I wouldn't be able to face our founders
after I die.
That sounds easy to say.
I'm afraid that
if the Jianmu Tree spell is activated,
given your bad luck,
you might die.
You...
Miss Xin,
we are about to begin.
You may excuse yourself.
Don't worry.